<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Don&#39;t Think Too Much</title>
    <link>https://randyyaj.github.io/tags/one-day-with/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Don&#39;t Think Too Much</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://randyyaj.github.io/tags/one-day-with/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>One day with - Emacs</title>
      <link>https://randyyaj.github.io/post/20151014_one_day_with/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 17:43:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://randyyaj.github.io/post/20151014_one_day_with/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I typically use Vi as my terminal editor of choice. However after recently talking with a colleague about Emacs as his terminal editor of choice; he intrigued me to using it. Now I&amp;rsquo;ve opened up Emacs in the past before but that was just from accidentally opening it in the terminal. This week I decided to actually learn it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post I will write my daily thoughts, likes and dislikes, and what I learned that may help beginners trying to pick up this tool. In addition, to stay true to this post I decided to write this whole post in emacs. What better way to learn something than to just use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;up-and-running&#34;&gt;Up and Running&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So coming in fresh I had no idea what C-x C-c meant. Like I literally hit shift c + x shift c + c. After a little googling I find out that the C in C-x is actually the control key. So now looking back C-x C-c really is just key sequence Ctrl + x + c.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also at first had no idea what M-f meant. Browsing stackoverflow helped me out on this one. Apparently M is the meta key so in this case since I was using a Mac machine M is the option/alt key. In windows it is the windows or super key. The weird thing about it was that the option key also made my Mac output funky text like this ƒ and ∫ when I try to use Meta + f and Meta + b. The solution to that problem was either to modify my terminal(iTerm2) settings to make the Meta key behave like a Meta key or use the escape key. I chose to do the former as it was easier to reach the option key for me. So to make this post easier for beginners I will refer to C as Ctrl and M as Meta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started I decided to learn the typical workflow patterns all editors should offer which are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;copy/cut and paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;undo and redo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;search and replace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;installing plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing this post there were several occasions where I needed to cut and paste some lines. I looked at this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rgrjr.com/emacs/emacs_cheat.html&#34;&gt;cheat sheet&lt;/a&gt; and easily enough all I had to do was mark the starting point with Ctrl + Space and then go to the end of the desired location and hit Ctrl + w. It also helps that you can copy a whole line by issuing Ctrl + k.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undo and redo was weird for me as I am used to doing Ctrl+r for redo and hitting u to undo in vim.
The first thing I had to learn was what the heck the command for undo Ctrl+/ and redo Ctrl+g+/ was.
Sometimes I would get weird behaviors when trying to redo changes but that may just be me not being use to emacs yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The search and replace feature took me a few tries but I eventually got it. To search was relatively easy just hit Ctrl+s and start typing the word you want to find. The replace functionality was slightly more involved. To replace you had to hit Meta+% (Meta+Shift+5). Which will ask you to find the word to search for (hit enter) then the word to replace with (hit enter). Lastly it&amp;rsquo;ll ask if you want to replace it. I had hit enter a couple times and it kept saying I had 0 occurrences. Finally I decided to hit the y key instead and it finally replaced the word for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The navigation in emacs is a breeze as all arrow keys work and using Ctrl+v and Meta+v I was able to do page up and page down. Jumping words were also easy as I could just hit the sequence Meta key + arrow-Left or arrow-Right to jump words vs Meta+f Meta+b. But for productivity I can see where Meta+f and Meta+b can be more resourceful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing plugins has always been one of those things I hated but needed the most for vim. Sometimes things work other times its a complete disaster. So I was really hoping that emacs would be easier and decided to try installing a plugin to see for myself. The plugin I decided to try was a markdown plugin seeing as this post was written in markdown I figured hey why not. A little bit of googling and I happened to stumble upon this link &lt;a href=&#34;http://emacswiki.org/emacs/MarkdownMode&#34;&gt;Emacs Markdown Mode&lt;/a&gt;. Now I have never done this before so it all looks scary new to me. The first few attempts really sucked as I had no idea what was wrong. I read the documentation on the plugin site multiple times and had no luck. I eventually got it to work after upgrading my Emacs version to the latest version. In doing so, the editor also allowed me to do visual selection - hold shift and using the arrow keys. I thought that was pretty cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardest part for me was tying to un-train myself from using vim commands that I was so use to. I found myself constantly wanting to hit :w or run vim commands. Even when revisiting this post I sometimes open it via the vim command first. Had to resist the urges&amp;hellip; must resist. From time to time I did happen to open the debugger window due to trained vim keystrokes. The way to get out of the debugger was pretty straight forward as I just hit the q key but sometimes it didn&amp;rsquo;t work so I had to do something like Ctrl+1 to kill the window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day I felt pretty confident with the basic emacs skills I developed and do think that it is a great and easy tool to pick up with a minimal learning curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;likes&#34;&gt;Likes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like that the editor has only one mode. Unlike vim there are different modes that maybe intimidating to new users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like that the arrow keys work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto-saving. I can&amp;rsquo;t tell you how much I want this in Vi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emacs feels like an IDE where you can customize language specific features with different modes via the Ctrl key combination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dislikes&#34;&gt;Dislikes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Undo and redo works weird. I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to wrap my head around this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frustrating help window that refuses to close. I eventually got it to close by issuing Ctrl+1.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wish there was a package manager to maintain the installation of the plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;resource-used&#34;&gt;Resource used&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rgrjr.com/emacs/emacs_cheat.html&#34;&gt;Emacs Cheat Sheet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/doc/doc.html&#34;&gt;GNU Emacs Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-learned&#34;&gt;What I learned&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt that emacs was a really easy editor to start working in once you understood how the macros work.
The workflow was somewhat smooth for a one day use I suppose it gets easier with time.
The C and M keys are really Ctrl and Meta. The sequence gets easier once you understand the pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Macros that benefited me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl + Space //marked location
Ctrl + w     //cut location
Ctrl + y     //paste
Ctrl + k     //cut whole line

//undo:
Ctrl + _
Ctrl + /

//redo:
Ctrl + g + _
Ctrl + g + /
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;would-i-ever-use-it-again&#34;&gt;Would I ever use it again&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure. But I think I&amp;rsquo;ll stick with Vi for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>