<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Don&#39;t Think Too Much</title>
    <link>https://randyyaj.github.io/tags/inkscape/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Don&#39;t Think Too Much</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://randyyaj.github.io/tags/inkscape/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Inkscape - Analysis of 2D Game Art (Denki Word Quest)</title>
      <link>https://randyyaj.github.io/post/20151014_inkscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 17:43:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://randyyaj.github.io/post/20151014_inkscape/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;Preface&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post we will cover the art style of the game Word Quest made by Denki.
We will examine the artwork and then recreate it using Inkscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copyright Disclaimer: I do not own the rights to Word Quest. All work done here is for the sole purpose of study.  All rights belong to it&amp;rsquo;s rightful owner(s). No copyright infringement intended.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/45209445/blog_posts/denki_word_quest_breakdown.svg&#34;&gt;Download SVG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;analysis&#34;&gt;Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image below is a picture of the game Word Quest. I will be showing you how to create the character,
the tree behind him, and also the rocks he is standing on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look carefully you can see that the tree is re-used through out the scene with very minor
detail add-ons. See the last tree on the right its the same tree.
Actually all of them are except the one funky tree that stands in the middle.
The artists scaled the same tree and reused it through out the scene without having to create new trees which saved both
time and money. The same goes for the rocks. If you look at all the rocks they vary in sizes and all look different.
However, with close examination, you can tell all the rocks are in fact the same.
They have just been scaled differently. Neat trick huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; src=&#34;http://i.ytimg.com/vi/azk9rFZJ_cs/maxresdefault.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-breakdown&#34;&gt;The Breakdown&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this section we will go into what I call the breakdown. I&amp;rsquo;ll show you the line art, color, and composition
used to create the game assets. I have also provided the svg file so that you can study it yourself.
The download link is located in the preface at the top. Although this artwork was probably made in illustrator
I dont have that kind of money to spare so I used inkscape instead. However, it should be easy enough to follow along
in your vector editor of choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; src=&#34;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/45209445/blog_posts/word_quest_breakdown.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see the art is quite easy to mimic and also looks really cool. The artists did a great job stacking
together the different layers as it almost gives it a paper cut out effect. Another thing to note is the
water color like texture found on the grass and funky tree. You can achieve this look in inkscape using the
pattern/spray tool and move it around as you like with the tweak tool. I will cover those in future tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you enjoyed this game art breakdown and would like to see more please
leave a comment below. Stay tuned and thanks again for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>