<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Don&#39;t Think Too Much</title>
    <link>https://randyyaj.github.io/tags/beer/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Don&#39;t Think Too Much</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://randyyaj.github.io/tags/beer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Beer Brewing</title>
      <link>https://randyyaj.github.io/post/20160504_beer_brewing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 12:30:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://randyyaj.github.io/post/20160504_beer_brewing/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am a big beer enthusiast. I love beer of all sorts and wanted to give a shot
at making my own. On my birthday my wife bought me an American Pale Ale brew kit from &lt;a href=&#34;https://craftabrew.com/&#34;&gt;Craft a Brew&lt;/a&gt; and we had the pleasure to brew it and try it.
I&amp;rsquo;m writing this review for anyone interested in brewing or just want to read about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-kit&#34;&gt;The Kit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kit came in a box that was beautifully designed even the instruction book was nice to look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the kit included these equipments
- 1 Gallon Carboy
- Air lock
- Drilled rubber stopper
- Transfer tubing
- Racking cane
- Thermometer
- Funnel
- Tube Clamp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bag Contents
- Malt Extract (Powder)
- Specialty Grains
- Hops
- Yeast
- Sanitizer
- Grain Nag&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up buying these things
- A sink strainer. It fits perfectly on the funnel.
- Ice
- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Glass-Beer-Bottle-Pack-Amber/dp/B018V24Q0I?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;redirect=true&amp;amp;ref_=oh_aui_detailpage_o01_s01&#34;&gt;Swing Top Bottles&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Star-San-2883-Acid-Sanitizer/dp/B01467UGN8?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;redirect=true&amp;amp;ref_=oh_aui_detailpage_o00_s01&#34;&gt;StarSan&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Empty-Amber-Glass-Spray-Bottle/dp/B00MU7R52M?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;redirect=true&amp;amp;ref_=oh_aui_detailpage_o00_s00&#34;&gt;Spray Bottle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; src=&#34;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/45209445/brewing/20160413_165950.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The swing bottles were something I chose because I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go through the
hassle of also buying a beer capper and caps and mostly because I&amp;rsquo;m lazy and just
needed something fast and easy to use. The StarSan was definitely not needed as the
kit came with its own sanitizer. Although, I do have to say that I prefer the StarSan
solely because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel soapy. The strainer was somewhat useful but next time
I would substitute it with a hop filter screen and just avoid messing with hops going into the brew altogether. I put the StarSan in to the spray bottle and used it to sanitize my work area and equipments. Again the StarSan is definitely optional and you can just use disinfectant wipes or something just make sure the work area is clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The steps in the instruction manual were good but still sort of confusing.
Watching this video helped a ton. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/CraftaBrew&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/user/CraftaBrew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-went-right&#34;&gt;What went right&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost everything went right actually. The sanitizing and cooking portion of the brew was pretty straight forward although it did take some time. I just had to make sure that the water wasn&amp;rsquo;t too hot to steep the barley. The bottling portion was easy too just had to make sure I knew how to use the friggin siphon. My wife helped me out on this one and we eventually got it working. Just a tip buy and auto siphon saves you so much trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;49%&#34; src=&#34;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/45209445/brewing/brewing_pot.jpg&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img width=&#34;49%&#34; src=&#34;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/45209445/brewing/carboy.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-went-wrong&#34;&gt;What went wrong&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my friggin bottles exploded! Man I only read about this happening but didn&amp;rsquo;t
expect it to happen to me. It seems that one of the bottle&amp;rsquo;s quality was pretty shitty after examining the bottle and looking at the inside glass it was prevalent that the bottle was thinner on one side. The scary part was I had plans on gifting this batch to friends and was afraid the bottle might explode on them. They are okay. Also an added note is make sure you add the correct sugar portion accordingly to your bottle size. I was using the 16oz bottles and that could have contributed to the bottle bomb. &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; would make a bottle bomb again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;review&#34;&gt;Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But how did the beer taste man!?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a month of waiting we finally tasted the beer and to our surprise it was quite
refreshing and tasty. The taste was similar to that of Sierra Nevada&amp;rsquo;s Pale Ale
which I really enjoy. The color was nice too although it was chill hazed when we got
it out of the fridge. No problem still tasted amazing. The alcohol kicked in fast and gave me a nice buzz it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too powerful but you can definitely tell it was there. The smell of the beer was fantastic and even during the fermentation process it was a joy to take in. Overall, I think this beer brewing kit was pretty straight forward and the beer that we produced was very good. I would highly recommend people who wants to start to give this kit a go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>